<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Acafeed Generated Feed</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml</link>
    <description>This feed is generated by Acafeed.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:26:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient perovskite/Cu(In,Ga)Se&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tandem solar cells with a composite intermediate recombination layer</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-67350-y</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Communications, Published online: 10 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-67350-y"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41467-025-67350-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Challenges remain in optimizing efficiency and stability of monolithic perovskite/Cu(In,Ga)Se2 (CIGS) tandem solar cells. Here, authors develop a composite-structured intermediate recombination layer and achieve maximum efficiency of 28.04% and 30.71% for 0.51 cm2 and 0.15 cm2 cells, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-67350-y</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-metallic magnetic Purcell enhancement in a thermally stable room-temperature maser</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-66016-z</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Communications, Published online: 10 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-66016-z"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41467-025-66016-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Dielectric structures that enhance magnetic emission are key for quantum devices but often suffer from thermal instability. Here, the authors realize a dielectric-free, compact metallic resonator with strong Purcell enhancement, enabling stable room-temperature maser action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-66016-z</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep-blue light-emitting diodes based on perovskite single-crystal thin films | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8060</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Metal halide perovskite light-emitting diodes (LEDs) are transformative optoelectronic platforms due to their tunable emission, high color purity, and broad color gamut. Nevertheless, the realization of high-luminance blue LEDs, particularly in the deep-blue spectral region, remains challenging compared to their green and red counterparts. This disparity is primarily attributed to the impaired charge transport kinetics and severe nonradiative recombination, both induced by the structural defects in wide-bandgap perovskites. Here, we address this issue through in situ growth of deep-blue–emitting perovskite single-crystal thin films (SCTFs). The resulting SCTFs exhibit exceptional crystallographic orientation, long-range structural ordering, and atomic-level smooth surfaces with a root mean square roughness of 109 picometers. In addition, the SCTFs show a low trap density of 6.9 × 10
    &lt;sup&gt;
     14
    &lt;/sup&gt;
    per cubic centimeter. These structural advantages translate to a high photoluminescence quantum yield of 48% and suppressed nonradiative recombination, enabling deep-blue LEDs with a maximum electroluminescence luminance of 179 candelas per square meter at 419 nanometers.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8060</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct imaging of facet development during growth of single-crystal covalent organic frameworks | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8131</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Single-crystal covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have received increasing interest due to their well-defined structures and exceptional performance. However, the reaction pathways of the facet development during growth of single-crystal COFs remains unclear, limiting the regulation of their shapes and functions. We report the dynamic imaging of the facet development during single-crystal COF-300 microcrystal growth using in situ dark-field optical microscopy. Our observations reveal that the concentration of terephthalaldehyde (BDA) linkers not only influences the morphology of the primary COF-300 crystal seeds but also governs the facet evolution, leading to the generation of differently shaped COF-300 microcrystals. Mechanistic studies reveal that the observed shape evolution of COF-300 single crystals arises from distinct kinetically or thermodynamically controlled growth pathways, depending on the BDA concentration. Moreover, we uncover the shape-dependent deformation capacity after solvent uptake, demonstrating the impact of COF-300 crystal morphology on its performance. These discoveries elucidate the COF facet transition mechanism and offer guidance for the future design of single-crystal COFs.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8131</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking megawatt-peak-power laser emission with colloidal quantum dots | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea8326</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Output power of a laser device critically defines the application prospects. Colloidal quantum dots (QDs) have emerged as auspicious laser media; however, the exclusively low-power emission obscures the practical deployment. Here, we resolve this challenge by designing an architecture of QD laser with unprecedented peak powers in megawatt regime. The achievement is enabled by integrating the QDs with exceptional gain metrics with a seed-amplifier laser structure. Transient spectroscopy and theoretical simulation reveal that the narrow emission linewidth and large biexciton binding energy of the QDs act synergistically to enable an enhanced gain performance with submonoexcitonic threshold and record high–saturated gain cross section. A Littman-Metcalf cavity is designed to deliver the continuously tunable laser emission, and the synchronous amplification reaches the megawatt output. The high-power QD laser exhibits high spatial coherence, linear polarization, and operational endurance, which has proved effective as the pump source for spectroscopic research.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea8326</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outcompeting hydrofunctionalization: Asymmetric remote substitution of alkynes | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aeb0726</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Propargylic substitution is a broadly studied basic reaction but requires a vicinal leaving group in the alkyne substrate. Here, we describe the first asymmetric remote substitution of alkynes bearing a linear alkyl-linked remote leaving group via synergistic Pd/amine catalysis. A set of modified diamine organocatalysts guarantees the high regio-, geometry- and enantioselectivity of the remote coupling between alkynes and aldehydes, during which conventionally more competitive hydrofunctionalization process is completely inhibited. Scale-up test and various derivatizations show the reliability and value of the protocol. Mechanistic studies suggest that the formation of crucial 1,3-diene intermediate from alkyne and a complex redox pathway of Pd metal are involved in the catalytic cycle.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aeb0726</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic Su–Schrieffer–Heeger chains with strong coupling amplitudes | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea3844</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Plasmonic many-particle systems with precisely tuned resonances and coupling strengths can exhibit emergent collective properties governed by universal principles. In one-dimensional chains with alternating couplings, known as Su–Schrieffer–Heeger (SSH) systems, this includes the formation of topologically protected mid-gap modes whose intensities localize at the chain’s ends. This subwavelength localization at optical frequencies is crucial for achieving strong coupling of mid-gap modes to two-level systems under ambient conditions, extending topological protection to hybrid light–matter states. Here, we have fabricated SSH chains from plasmonic nanoslit resonators with strong interresonator coupling. The alternating distance between the nanoslit resonators is controlled with subnanometer precision, enabling accurate prediction and experimental observation of topologically protected mid-gap modes via photoemission electron microscopy. Our results open the path toward experimental realizations of two-dimensional photonic metasurfaces exhibiting higher-order topological modes that can be strongly coupled to single emitters and quantum materials at ambient conditions.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea3844</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
