<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AI-Assisted Academic Feed</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml</link>
    <description>This feed is generated by Acafeed.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Forced bond ionization–driven design of ultralow lattice thermal conductivity materials for flexible thermoelectrics | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz7487</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    The search for development strategies that yield low κ
    &lt;sub&gt;
     lat
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    has become the focus of thermoelectrics and barrier coatings. Here, we propose a “forced bond ionization” strategy by integrating conflicting coordination environments (planar three coordination versus tetrahedral four coordination of Cu) to form pseudo-tetrahedral structures. This approach induces partial ionization of Cu─I bonds in Cu
    &lt;sub&gt;
     5
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    TeS
    &lt;sub&gt;
     3
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    I
    &lt;sub&gt;
     3
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    (CTSI), yielding a record-low κ
    &lt;sub&gt;
     lat
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    of 0.17 W/(m·K) for dense inorganic polycrystals. The pseudo-tetrahedral configuration triggers shear modes, markedly reducing the transverse speed of sound (ν
    &lt;sub&gt;
     T
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    = 839 m/s) and amplifying anharmonicity (Grüneisen parameter γ = 2.76). Theoretical analysis reveals that coordination preference competition provides Cu atoms a metastable site, promoting the disordered behavior. The corresponding vibrations of I atoms and disordered Cu atoms dominate the phonon scattering while the material having remarkable flexibility and certain thermoelectric potential. This work establishes a bond ionization–driven design paradigm for ultralow κ
    &lt;sub&gt;
     lat
    &lt;/sub&gt;
    materials, marking a leap toward potential flexible thermoelectric applications.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz7487</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17-GHz lossless InP-membrane active metasurface | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea3538</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    High-speed active metasurfaces enable spatiotemporal light control within an ultrathin device layer, offering previously unexplored possibilities for optical communication, sensing, and computing. However, a trade-off between electrical conductivity and optical loss has hindered the realization of a high-speed, low-loss device. Here, we experimentally demonstrate an active metasurface operating at 1.5-μm wavelength range that achieves a record-high 17.5-GHz modulation bandwidth while maintaining a high quality (
    &lt;i&gt;
     Q
    &lt;/i&gt;
    ) factor of 102 and an ultralow optical loss of 0.56 dB. This is enabled by the indium phosphide (InP) membrane platform, where n-InP offers high electron mobility and low free-carrier absorption simultaneously. A high-
    &lt;i&gt;
     Q
    &lt;/i&gt;
    Friedrich-Wintgen quasi-bound-state-in-the-continuum mode within the InP-membrane high-contrast grating (InP HCG) traps light in the organic electro-optic material for efficient modulation. The InP HCG also functions as an ultralow-resistance interdigitated electrode, enabling 50-fold faster modulation than silicon-based counterparts. Our work paves the way toward active metasurfaces for high-speed spatiotemporal light control beyond the GHz regime.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.aea3538</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrical control of photon spin angular momentum in organic electroluminescent materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01780-4</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Photonics, Published online: 26 November 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01780-4"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41566-025-01780-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Electrical tuning of the recombination zone in circularly polarized (CP) OLEDs enables switching the CP generation mechanism between normal and anomalous CP electroluminescence. This is exploited to electrically control the handedness of emitted CP light from the same device with the same enantiomer material.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01780-4</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving electron microscopy with light</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01798-8</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Photonics, Published online: 02 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01798-8"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41566-025-01798-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Shining intense laser pulses on an electron beam in an electron microscope corrects electron-optical spherical aberration, paving the way to using light to improve electron microscopy imaging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-025-01798-8</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
