<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AI-Assisted Academic Feed</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml</link>
    <description>This feed is generated by Acafeed.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JedimasterLu/acafeed/feedgenerator/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:08:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>VTA dopaminergic neuronal activity during NREM sleep is modulated by learning and facilitates motor memory consolidation | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adw7427</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    Memory consolidation enables animals to draw on past experiences to guide future behavior. This process involves system- and synaptic-level changes and predominantly occurs during sleep. While hippocampal-cortical circuits are well studied in this context, the contributions of other systems, including dopaminergic circuits—key players in learning-related processes—remain poorly understood. Ventral tegmental area dopaminergic (VTA
    &lt;sup&gt;
     DA
    &lt;/sup&gt;
    ) neurons are active during sleep and suggested to participate in memory consolidation processes; however, causal evidence for this is lacking. Using calcium-dependent fiber photometry, electrophysiology, and chemogenetic and optogenetic manipulations across learning paradigms, we explore the functions of VTA
    &lt;sup&gt;
     DA
    &lt;/sup&gt;
    neuronal activity during sleep. We show that VTA
    &lt;sup&gt;
     DA
    &lt;/sup&gt;
    activity during nonrapid eye movement sleep is experience dependent, is enhanced by motor skill and associative learning, facilitates motor skill memory consolidation, and exhibits a motor learning–dependent increase in temporal coordination with cortical spindle oscillations. Our findings uncover a previously unidentified function for VTA
    &lt;sup&gt;
     DA
    &lt;/sup&gt;
    neurons in consolidating memories during sleep, advancing understanding of this central neuromodulator’s functions in regulating fundamental biological processes.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adw7427</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T-SCAPE: T cell immunogenicity scoring via cross-domain aided predictive engine | Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8759</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="abstracts"&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;section id="abstract"&gt;
   &lt;h2&gt;
    Abstract
   &lt;/h2&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;
    T cell immunogenicity, the ability of peptide fragments to elicit T cell responses, is a critical determinant of the safety and efficacy of protein therapeutics and vaccines. While deep learning shows promise for in silico prediction, the scarcity of comprehensive immunogenicity data is a major challenge. We present T cell immunogenicity scoring via cross-domain aided predictive engine (T-SCAPE), a novel multidomain deep learning framework that leverages adversarial domain adaptation to integrate diverse immunologically relevant data sources, including major histocompatibility complex (MHC) presentation, peptide-MHC (pMHC) binding affinity, T cell receptor–pMHC interaction, source organism information, and T cell activation. Validated through rigorous leakage-controlled benchmarks, T-SCAPE demonstrates exceptional performance in predicting T cell activation for specific peptide-MHC pairs. It also accurately predicts the antidrug antibody–inducing potential of therapeutic antibodies without requiring MHC inputs. This success is attributed to T-SCAPE’s biologically grounded and data-driven multidomain pretraining. Its consistent and robust performance highlights its potential to advance the development of safer and more effective vaccines and protein therapeutics.
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adz8759</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atom-level enzyme active site scaffolding using RFdiffusion2</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02975-x</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Methods, Published online: 03 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02975-x"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41592-025-02975-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;RFdiffusion2, an extension of the RFdiffusion framework, builds de novo enzyme active sites using atom-level functional group constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02975-x</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C-COMPASS: a user-friendly neural network tool profiles cell compartments at protein and lipid levels</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02880-3</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Methods, Published online: 04 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02880-3"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41592-025-02880-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;C-COMPASS is an open-source software designed to predict the spatial cellular distribution of proteins and lipids from cellular organelle profiling using a neural network-based regression model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02880-3</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent space-based network analysis for brain–behavior linking in neuroimaging</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02896-9</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Methods, Published online: 04 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02896-9"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41592-025-02896-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;LatentSNA is a method for network analysis in human neuroimaging. It facilitates linking neural activity with behavior and improves biomarker prediction by reducing type II errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02896-9</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Imputation for Skeleton data (DISK) for behavioral science</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02893-y</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature Methods, Published online: 04 December 2025; &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02893-y"&gt;doi:10.1038/s41592-025-02893-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Analysis of behavioral data often involves tracking animal keypoints in video and motion capture recordings. DISK imputes missing keypoints, thereby improving downstream analyses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-025-02893-y</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
